Guide to the Liberty Hyde Bailey papers, 1845-2004
Bailey, Liberty Hyde papers, 1845-2004
- Series VI. Hortorium and Plant Collecting, 1887 - 1959
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Seychelles - Skottsberg, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Slate -Smith, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Smithers - Sylvan, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Taylor - Tordoff, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Toronto - Tuskegee, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ulich - Von Engeln, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Wagner - Walther, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ward - Weatherwax, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Weaver - Warnock, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Wharton - Who's, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Wicht - Wister, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Wolf - Zielinski, 1944 - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Abbey - Allen, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Alling - Anderson, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Antiquarian - Ayres, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Babcock - Bartholomew, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Bartlett - Benner, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Bennett - Blakeslee, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Blankestyn - Box, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Bracelin - Brownsville, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Brukardt - Byrum, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Calcutta - CARE, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Carleton - Chadwick, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Chamberlain - Clark, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Clausen - Combs, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Conard - Corsi, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Cory - Czech, 1946 - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Da Costa - Dayton, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Deam - Dimitri, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Dobbs - Douglas, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Dover - Duttons, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Eames - Ellison, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ellerbusch - Erwin, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Eustace - Eyster, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Faassen - Finlay, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Fischer - Fox, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: France - Furtado, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Gabelman - Gershoy, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Gibson - Government, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Grabau - Greystone, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Griest - Guthrie, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Haas - Halmos, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Hanes, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Haney - Harper, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Harrington - Head, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Heath, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Hedrick - Heuser, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Hicks - Hoefer, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Holl - Howlett, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Hulten - Hyland, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Illinois - Jerome, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Jessup - Johnston, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Jones - Kentucky, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Kever - Killip, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Kindig - Knudson, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Kobuski - Lapostolle, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Larson - Le Page's, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Levadoux - Lisboa, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Lisk - Lush, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: MacCaughey - Martin, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Mason - McBryde, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: McClelland - McVaugh, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Meehan - Meyer, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Miami - Mizwa, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Moe - Moldenke, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Monroe - Moore, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Moran - Moury, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Muenscher - Murphy, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Myers, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Nathan - New Zealand, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Nicholls - Oxford, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Orto - Patterson, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Pearce - Pennsylvania, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Pereda - Poe, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Pohl - Princeton, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Puerto Rico - Questel, 1946 - 1948 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ragonese - Raymond, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Reasoner - Robinson, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Rockefeller - Rollins, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ronk - Rowlee, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Royal Dutch Airlines - Runyon, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Rural Church Institute - Ryerson, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: St. John - Schweinfurth, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Science - Shaw, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Sheibley - Schultz, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Simmons - Smith, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Smithsonian, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Snyder - Stationery, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Steadman - Styer, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Sullivan - Sylvan, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Taber - Teagle, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Tegtmeier - Townes, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Transcontinental - Tyrell, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ulich - Vaughan's, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Veliz - Volz, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Wade - Weatherlow, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Webber - Whitaker, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: White - Willcox, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Williams - Wing, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Winkler - Work, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Worker - Zwart, 1946 - 1948 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ab - Air, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Albertson - Alp, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ama - Ames, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: And - Ard, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ash - Bak, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Bac - Ban, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Bar, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Bas - Ber, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Bi - Bl, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Bo - Bri, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Br - Bu, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Cachia - Cayuga, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ch - Ci, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Cl - Col, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Com - Con, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Coo - Cou, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Cra - Cut, 1949 - 1952 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Dac - Day, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Dea - Des, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Dic - Dy, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ea - Ei, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: El - Ew, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Fa - Fen, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Fie - Fox, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Fra - Fur, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ga - Gil, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Gim - Go, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Gra - Gut, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Haa - Han, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Hara - Harz, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Has - Hay, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Hea - Hem, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Hen - Hor, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Hos - Hz, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: I, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Jager - Japanese, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Je - Joh, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Joi - Jz, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ka - Kh, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Kia - Kz, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Laa - Lav, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Law, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Len - Ley, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Li - Liv, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Lo - Ly, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Maa - Max, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: McA - McZ, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Mei - Mey, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Mia - Mn, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Mol - Moo, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Mor - Mt, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Mu - Mv, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Myers, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Na - Nh, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ni - On, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Oo - Oz, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Paa - Pd, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Pea - Pk, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Pl - Q, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Raa - Red, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ree - Roa, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Rob - Rom, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ron - Rz, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Sa - Sch, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Sci - Shd, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: She - Sl, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Sma - Sn, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: So - Std, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Ste - Stq, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Str - Sz, 1949 - 1952 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Tai - Texas, 1949 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Thacker - Tiranti, 1949 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Todd - Trinidad, 1949 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Tukey - Utrecht, 1949 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: V, 1949 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Wadsworth - Watts, 1949 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Weatherby - West, 1949 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Wheeler - Wiggins, 1949 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Wilhelm - Witte, 1949 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: Wood - Z, 1949 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: A - C, 1953 - 1954 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: D - G, 1953 - 1954 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: H - K, 1953 - 1954 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: L - M, 1953 - 1954 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: N - R, 1953 - 1954 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: S - T, 1953 - 1954 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Hortorium Correspondence: U - Z, 1953 - 1954 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Ernest Braunton Correspondence, 1927-1929 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Caribbean trip notes, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Kioshan, Chikungshan travel notes,, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Notebook - Notes on Plants,, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - European Journal #1,, Sept. - Oct. 1888 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - European Journal #2,, Oct. - Dec. 1888 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Notebook - "No. 1: Ranunculaceae" (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hortorium Personal file, 1920 - 1952 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Agreement between Bailey and Cornell regarding the gift of the Hortorium, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Hortorium Mission Statement and related correspondence, 1935 - 1943 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Hortorium information & publications, 1937 - 1955 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Hortorium information & publications, 1956 - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Article notes and research for Baileya, 1954 - 1956 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Hortorium Articles: "Horticulture Magazine", 1956 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Hortorium Articles: "Seed World", 1956 - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Hortorium Articles: "American Nurseryman", 1956 - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Hortorium Articles: "Flower Grower", 1956 - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Hortorium Articles: "National Gardener", 1956 - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Hortorium Articles: "Popular Gardening", 1956 - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Hortorium Articles: "Tropical Homemaker & Gardener", 1956 - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Hortorium Articles: "American Agriculturalist", 1957 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Hortorium Articles: "MEGA: The Men's Gardening Magazine", 1957 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Notes and Article on Liberty Hyde Bailey's travels in Caribbean Islands and Bermuda, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Baileya, Mar. 1955 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Brochure: "The Length and Shadow of the Man", 1956 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Endowment Fund material, 1956 - 1958 (Box 14, Folder 36-37)
  - Information on the Hortorium, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Baileya, Mar. 1958 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Baileya, Jun-58 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Bound "Minutes of the Advisory Committee for the L.H. Bailey Hortorium Meetings 1-30, Also various other documents and reports", 1935 - 1947 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - L.H. Bailey Hortorium Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 1935 - 1937 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - L.H. Bailey Hortorium Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 1938 - 1941 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - L.H. Bailey Hortorium Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 1942 - 1944 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - L.H. Bailey Hortorium Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 1945 - 1947 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - L.H. Bailey Hortorium Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 1948 - 1949 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - L.H. Bailey Hortorium Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 1950 - 1954 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - L.H. Bailey Hortorium Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 1955 - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Advisory Council, 1946 - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Liberty Hyde Bailey Hortorium at Cornell University: A Story in Pictures, ca. 1959 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Thirteenth International Horticultural Congress - London, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Gift of the Hortorium - Copy, 1935 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Horticulture Schools, 1887 - 1896 (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Newsclippings: Horticulture, 1955 - 1958 (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - Baileya, 1957 (Box 46, Folder 47)
  - Baileygram, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 47)
  - Eugene Barker Correspondence and Article, 1920, 1944, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 50)
  - Notes on the History of Horticulture (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Series VII. Writings
  - "I Teach" poem by L. H. Bailey, Oct. 20, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Publication promotional material, 1890-1930 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Publication promotional material, 1890-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Publications, articles, file cards, 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Standard Cyclopedia of Horticulture" material, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Publications, articles, file cards, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Publications, articles, file cards, 1920-1947 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "The Grass Is Green" file card (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Armistice" file card, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Over the Hills and Far Away" file card (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "The Timeless Brook" file card, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "The Garden Flows" file card, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "I Was a Rail Splitter" file card, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Marvels at Our Feet" file card, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts, 1893-1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "A Child's Face at the Window" poem (fragile), 1897 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts, 1926-1928 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts, 1929-1932 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "The Creek and the Birds" manuscript, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Manuscripts: "Harvest Time," "Orange Farming at the Mouth of the Mississippi," "What is a Weed?", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "The Garden of Bellflowers" reviews, clippings, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "How I Went to Chicago", 1956 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Botanical Science and Its Applications" (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Poets and Prophets" partial manuscript (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "The Gardener" partial manuscript (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "North American Food Plants" (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Manuscripts: "Perils of over emphasis in the Rural Work," "A Neglected and Unoccupied Field," "A Panhandle Cow Ranch " (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous poetry fragments and notes (Box 2, Folder 37-40)
  - Manuscripts: "Gardening and Its Future", "Good Health and Good Farming", 1890 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "Wind and Weather" manuscript, A-B, 1904-1939 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - "Wind and Weather" manuscript, C-D, 1904-1939 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - "Wind and Weather" manuscript, E-G, 1907-1925 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - "Wind and Weather" manuscript, H-I, 1907-1925 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - "Wind and Weather" manuscript, J-M, 1907-1925 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "Wind and Weather" manuscript, N-P, 1911-1920 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "Wind and Weather" manuscript, R-S, 1911-1920 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - "Wind and Weather" manuscript, T-U, 1909-1920 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "Wind and Weather" manuscript, V-Y, 1909-1920 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - "Wind and Weather" miscellany, 1916-1934 (Box 2, Folder 51-52)
  - Mostly published writings authored, about, or compiled by Bailey, 1874-1950 (Box 17,19)
    Arranged in semi-chronological order
    - Birds Michigan State Pomological Society, Annual Report pages 127-128 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1874 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      2 copies; the essay was read before the society on September 4, 1873
    - A Catalogue of North American Carices Compiled as an Exchange List, a Check List for Herbaria, and as a Contribution to American Caricography Privately published 4 pages Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1874 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - The Garden Fence Wright & Potter Printing Co. State Printers Author: L. H. Bailey, 1886 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Lecture - read at the country meeting of the Massachusetts State Board of Agriculture at Framingham on December 1885
    - (Box 19, Folder 3)
      three envelopes with Bailey's printed photo
    - Things in a New Country Not Generally Appreciated Michigan State Agricultural Society, Annual Report Volume 15: pages 52-54 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1886 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      delivered in 1885
    - The Pollen Question Philadelphia Press Author: L. H. Bailey, 1886 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - A Trip Northward College Speculum Volume 6: pages 2-3 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1886 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Chippeway Plant Names Botanical Gazette Volume 12, No. 2: pages 37-39 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1887 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      2 copies
    - Horticultural Nomenclature and Phytography Agricultural Science pages 53-55 Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1887 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Horticultural Terminology I American Garden Author: L. H. Bailey, May 1887 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Horticultural Terminology II American Garden Author: L. H. Bailey, June 1887 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - The Origin of the Tomato from a Morphological Standpoint The American Naturalist Volume 21: 573-576 Author: L. H. Bailey, June 1887 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - A List of Ornamental Plants Which Are Hardy In Michigan Privately printed - Lansing, Michigan 13 pages Author: L. H. Bailey, July 1, 1887 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      prepared for a class in landscape gardening; 3 copies
    - Sketch of the Flora of Vermillion Lake and Vicinity Geological and Natural History Survey of Minnesota - Report on Botanical Work in Minnesota for the Year 1886 Bulletin 3, No. 3: pages 7-10 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1887 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Bailey's signature on the bulletin's cover
    - Plants Collected or Observed on the Bluff at Duluth, July 17, 1886 Geological and Natural History Survey of Minnesota - Report on Botanical Work in Minnesota for the Year 1886 Bulletin 3, No. 3: pages 44-45 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1887 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Plants Collected or Observed on Hunters' Island, British America, July 26 and 27, 1886 Geological and Natural History Survey of Minnesota - Report on Botanical Work in Minnesota for the Year 1886 Bulletin 3, No. 3: pages 55-56 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1887 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Annual Report of the Professor of Horticulture and Landscape Gardening Agricultural College of Michigan Bulletin 31: pages 1-96 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1887 (Box 19, Folder 13)